navaneeth.rajagopalan.05@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/navaneeth-rajagopalan-08444574



# **RAJAGOPALAN**

**NAVANEETH** 

# **PROFILE**

A post-graduate in Data Science and a highly enthusiastic and an avid programmer, a constant learner with 4.5+ years of demonstrated experience as a Software Developer, designing and implementing efficient software systems in collaboration with various stakeholders and team members.

# **EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS**

Master of Data Science	The University of Melbourne Parkville, Australia	85.143 WAM H1 - First Class Honours	2019 – 2020
Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering	Amrita Vishwa Vidyapeetham University Coimbatore, India	8.11 CGPA  Distinction	2010 – 2014

# **SKILLS**

REST API development	Application Development		
Node JS + Express JS	HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript	React JS	
Python FastAPI	Angular JS	Plotly JS	
	Leaflet JS	Android application development	
Programming Languages	Statistics, Machine Learning and Al		
Python 3.x JavaScript	Regression	Deep Learning	Clustering
R	Classification	Reinforcement Learning	PCA
Database Systems	Others		
Relational Database	Project Management	Customer Service	Team Management
NoSQL Database	GIT Version Management		

# **PROJECTS**

- Built a collaborative shared whiteboard application GUI using Java Swing and Java RMI for distributed message passing.
- Modelled a CNN and bi-LSTM based Binary Classifier using pre-trained Word2Vec embeddings for climate-change misinformation detection classifier employing NLP techniques.
- Modelled a Multi-Class Classifier model to solve the Authorship Attribution problem applying NLP techniques. Developed a Deep Neural Network using Word Embeddings based features to predict the author of a given tweet from 10,000 possible authors.
- Developed a Parallel Computing program to process 2.5 million Tweet records and extract features such as Geo Location of the Tweet and the Hashtags associated with it. Python Message Passing Interface (MPI) library - MPI4Py was used to communicate and parallel process the tweets across the nodes on the University of Melbourne's High-Performance Computing (HPC) system.
- Developed a software system comprising of an Angular 7 Web Application with Plotly JS and a Couch DB (NoSQL Database) for data storage. Designed and developed a Multi-Threaded Twitter data harvester to collect and process the tweets from across Greater Melbourne. The software system was deployed on the cloud platform (NeCTAR).

## **WORK EXPERIENCES**

# Industry Project – The University of Melbourne (Master of Data Science)

# **DQUBE Solutions, Melbourne, Australia**

Mar 2020 to Dec 2020

- Led and worked with a student team of 5 members to implement a **Sentiment Classifier** that can predict the sentiment of a domain-independent review-based text.
- Designed the Web API workflow to enable any down-stream client application to access the sentiment classifier over a Web API and request for the sentiment prediction on any text. Implemented the RESTful Web API using the Python 3.x based FastAPI framework and deployed using Docker container.

# **Software Engineer Intern**

Melbourne Data Analytics Platform (MDAP), The University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Australia

Dec 2019 to Feb 2020

- Designed and developed the "Circuit Creative Convergence", a data-centric web application for **Geospatial visualization**. The application maps the theatre companies' tours across Australia.
- Collaborated with the stakeholders at the Digital Studio Faculty of Arts (The University of Melbourne) periodically for the progressive development of the application.
- Carried out Data Engineering tasks by collecting geospatial data and processing it for visualization.
- Developed the web application using Angular JS, HTML5, CSS3 and Leaflet JS for front-end. The back-end infrastructure was
  developed using PostgreSQL database, REST API with Node JS, and Express JS.

# **Advanced Analytics Intern**

# Coles Group, Melbourne, Australia

Jul 2019 to Oct 2019

- Collaborated with a dynamic team of interns with varied skill sets, to build a **customer segmentation model** to derive insights on customer shopping behaviour for a selected product category.
- Performed Data Engineering queried the customer and product data from an Oracle Database and pre-processed using R.
- Implemented Clustering (Unsupervised Learning) in R to identify the potential customer groups for segment profiling.

# **Project Leader**

# Soliton Technologies Pvt Ltd, Coimbatore, India

May 2017 to Jan 2019

- Led multiple offshore development teams for **GUI application development**, managing projects from pre-sales until project delivery and closure. Main activities involved customer interaction for requirements gathering and analysis, estimation, onboarding the development team, project kick-off, following an **Agile software development workflow**.
- Developed web-based GUIs using **Angular JS**, **HTML5**, **CSS3**, **Node JS** and **Express JS** and maintained the **Git workflow** and streamlined the version controlling for the projects.
- Built a **native Android application** using **Android Studio** for the organization's internal use with the **Web API** server implemented with **Node JS** and **Express JS** in and deployed in **Google Firebase** utilizing the **Cloud Firestore** (**NoSQL database**) for data storage.
- Engaged in sales activities by proactively reached out to the clients to showcase the work accomplished with the newly adapted GUI development framework and the value additions from the enriched UI/UX in the GUIs. Enabling Soliton in acquiring 3 new GUI projects from China and Germany with revenue impact of about **USD 45,000**.
- Provided quality deliverables and highly appreciated customer experiences which led to signing up of multiple new projects leading to a **100% increase in revenue** generated from the team in less than a year.

# **Senior Systems Engineer**

# Infosys Limited, Bangalore, India

Jun 2014 to May 2017

- Developed 3-Tier architecture Web Applications using .NET Framework following a Waterfall software development workflow.
- Implemented Front-End and Middleware layer using ASP .NET with C#, MVC .NET with C#, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery.
- Devised the database schemas for the application architecture design. Constructed and deployed database entities like Tables, Views and Stored Procedures and performing query optimizations in MS SQL Server database.

## AWARDS AND RECOGNITIONS

- Soliton Technologies Excellence Award for providing stellar customer experience with demonstrated evidence of People, Process and Technology coming together seamlessly.
- Client recognition Citizens Bank CREDO All-Star Performance Award for going the extra mile and providing.
- Infosys Ltd Financial Service unit's Insta Award for critical project support catalysing successful delivery of the project.

### REFERENCES